Lance T. Wilhelm

Joint Base Lewis-McChord, WA **Physicist** lance.wilhelm@gatech.edu

lancewilhelm.github.io github.com/lancewilhelm linkedin.com/in/lance-wilhelm

Experienced team/laboratory leader with a demonstrated history of working in the research industry. Skilled in Analytics, Scientific Management, Leadership, and Innovation. Strong operations professional with a Master of Science in Analytics from the Georgia Institute of Technology and a Bachelor of Science in Physics from the United States Air Force Academy. Currently enrolled in the Master of Science in Computer Science program at Georgia Tech.

EXPERIENCE

Director of Operations

May 2022 — Present

361st Recruiting Squadron

Joint Base Lewis-McChord, WA

- Drives daily operations for an 84-member recruiting squadron in 34 offices across 721K square miles
- Coordinates with squadron leadership to enact Commander's intent and strategic vision
- Oversees squadron operations flight responsible for 3 Military Entrance Processing stations and recruiting administrative actions
- Utilizes analytics subject matter expertise to create novel reports on recruiting operations

Support Flight Commander

Nov 2020 — May 2022

361st Recruiting Squadron

Joint Base Lewis-McChord, WA

- · Led squadron's Support Flight and oversaw Commander Support Staff, Communications, Logistics, and Personnel Sections
- Stewarded \$1.5M budget, 652 communication equipment items, 60 GOV fleet, and 34 offices across 721K miles supporting 74 recruiters
- Primary squadron Approving Official validating Operation and Maintenance and Advertising government purchase card (GPC) accounts
- · Oversaw civilian personnel management and appraisal as direct supervisor and higher level reviewer for 5 personnel

Chief of Laboratory Operations

Jun 2017 — Nov 2020

Harkins Laboratory Complex, AFTAC • Managed day-to-day operations for a multi-million dollar laboratory complex Cheyenne Mountain AFS, CO

The complex operates two research lab facilities to conduct research and development in ultra-low background radiological analysis methods

Director of Operations

Feb 2017 — Jun 2017

AFRL Maker Hub

Wright-Patterson AFB, OH

- Ensured continuous operation of an innovative learning and rapid prototyping environment available to over 10,000 government employees
- Extended network of AFRL external and internal resources to provide assistance to users looking to collaborate with nontraditional partners
- Acted as subject matter expert to the Hub's capabilities including, but not limited to rapid prototyping, CAD/CAM design, additive manufacturing, CNC technologies, microcontrollers, small electronics, code development, and general fabrication techniques

Executive Officer

Nov 2015 — Feb 2017

Materials and Manufacturing Directorate, AFRL

- Wright-Patterson AFB, OH Provided executive support to SES Director and O-6 Deputy Director. Planned and executed critical directorate-level taskings
- Executed emergency management procedures for a 900-person Directorate with a \$750M annual budget and \$500M research and development complex
- Directed special job openings to eligible military members. Oversaw nomination procedures to max options for career growth

Non-Destructive Evaluation Engineer

Aug 2013 — Nov 2015

Materials and Manufacturing Directorate, AFRL

Wright-Patterson AFB, OH

- Conducted in-house research to improve nondestructive inspection (NDI) capability used to ensure structural integrity
- Led over \$6M in Nondestructive Evaluation Research and Development, including a high-vis Advanced Technology
- · Developed strategy for advancing eddy-current-based Nondestructive Investigation technologies to enhance aircraft structural integrity evaluations

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Analytics, Georgia Institute of Technology **Bachelor of Science in Physics**, *United States Air Force Academy* Dec 2022

May 2013

SKILLS

Tools and Languages Python, R, Git, ŁTFX, MarkDown, SQL, C, Java **Quantitative Research** AI/ML/DL, Tableau, Power BI

Lance T. Wilhelm

Joint Base Lewis-McChord, WA lance.wilhelm@gatech.edu

Physicist

lancewilhelm.github.io github.com/lancewilhelm linkedin.com/in/lance-wilhelm

CERTIFICATIONS

Flight Commander Course, Space Launch Delta 45Apr 2019Level II Science & Technology Management, Defense Acquisition UniversitySep 2016Level I Engineering, Defense Acquisition UniversityApr 2016

PUBLICATIONS

W. Jin and L. Wilhelm. The hateful memes challenge next move, 2022. https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2212.06655.

R. L. Balthazor, M. G. McHarg, C. L. Enloe, B. Mueller, D. J. Barnhart, Z. W. Hoeffner, R. Brown, L. Scherliess, and L. T. Wilhelm. Methodology of evaluating the science benefit of various satellite/sensor constellation orbital parameters to an assimilative data forecast model. *Radio Science*, 50(4):318–326, 2015. https://doi.org/10.1002/2014RS005426.

AWARDS

Lance P. Sijan Leadership Award, CGO Nominee, 372nd Recruiting Group	2022
CGO of the Quarter, Team McChord	1QCY22, 3QCY21
Support Flight of the Quarter, Air Force Recruiting Service	2QFY22
CGO of the Year, 361st Recruiting Squadron	CY21
CGO of the Quarter, Air Force Recruiting Service	1QCY21